<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! I&#39;m Mohammed Tayeh 😄</title>
    <link>https://tayeh.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hi! I&#39;m Mohammed Tayeh 😄</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:52:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tayeh.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digitalocean Kubernetes Challenge 2021 - Harbor</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/posts/digitalocean-kubernetes-challenge-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 18:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/posts/digitalocean-kubernetes-challenge-2021/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this is guide i will explain how to create a Kubernetes Cluster on Digitalocean using Terraform, then i will deploy the Harbor on Cluster as a internal container registry
Terraform Files the terraform code used to create the cluster
resource &amp;#34;digitalocean_kubernetes_cluster&amp;#34; &amp;#34;tayeh-cluster&amp;#34; { name = &amp;#34;tayeh-cluster&amp;#34; region = &amp;#34;fra1&amp;#34; version = &amp;#34;1.21.5-do.0&amp;#34; node_pool { name = &amp;#34;worker-pool&amp;#34; size = &amp;#34;s-1vcpu-2gb&amp;#34; node_count = 3 auto_scale = true min_nodes = 3 max_nodes = 4 } } after prepare the Terraform code execute this command to apply it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install PHP 8 on CentOS 7/8 and Fedora</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/posts/install_php8_centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:58:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/posts/install_php8_centos/</guid>
      <description>Install the EPEL repository  CentOS 8  dnf install https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/epel-release-latest-8.noarch.rpm  CentOS 7  yum install https://dl.fedoraproject.org/pub/epel/epel-release-latest-7.noarch.rpm  Fedora 33  dnf install https://rpms.remirepo.net/fedora/remi-release-33.rpm Install the Remi repository  CentOS 8  dnf install https://rpms.remirepo.net/enterprise/remi-release-8.rpm  CentOS 7  yum install https://rpms.remirepo.net/enterprise/remi-release-7.rpm  Fedora 33  dnf config-manager --set-enabled remi Install the yum-utils package  CentOS 8  dnf install yum-utils  CentOS 7  yum install yum-utils Enable the module stream for PHP 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install the NVIDIA drivers on Fedora 33 with Hybrid Switchable Graphics</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/posts/install_the_nvidia_drivers_on_fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 09:27:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/posts/install_the_nvidia_drivers_on_fedora/</guid>
      <description>This is guide, how to install NVIDIA proprietary drivers on Fedora 33 with Hybrid Switchable Graphics [Intel + Nvidia GeForce]
 Backup important files before you start installation. And this is of course at your own risk, because graphic cards, components and monitors are different and some combinations might cause totally unexpected results.
 identify your Nvidia graphic lspci -vnn | grep VGA the output of the above command will be like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to automate a deploy with GitHub actions via SSH</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/posts/github_actions_via_ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:07:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/posts/github_actions_via_ssh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction GitHub Actions is an API for cause and effect on GitHub: orchestrate any workflow, based on any event, while GitHub manages the execution, provides rich feedback, and secures every step along the way.
In this article, we will be exploring a hands-on approach to managing your CD processes using GitHub Actions via SSH.
The workflow:
 Connect to VPS via SSH Move to project directory git pull the new changes execute any necessary command  Prerequisites  A GitHub account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Me</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:00:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/support/</guid>
      <description>Oh Wow, you’re actually checking this page! Thank you so much for your interest, and because I don’t want to waste your time, let’s jump right into it.
I love making tutorials, and I’m amazed by all the positive feedback and requests I’m receiving every day. but of course, all of this takes a lot of time and energy.
I want to maintain everything always FREE and accessible to everyone, and of course, the gratitude and a number of comments from subscribers and followers are the best rewards I can expect, but sometimes you need a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 13:11:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/uses/</guid>
      <description>Here are the things I use which keeps me productive.
Hardware  I use HP OMEN 15 (2020). It is a fast machine, Intel Core i7-10750H Hexa-Core, 20GB of DDR4 RAM, 512Gb NVMe SSD, NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1660Ti (6GB GDDR6). I am currently using iPhone 7 as my phone. It is an old device, but it still feels fast. I am planning to upgrade it (support).  Operating System  I use Linux for my day job as a primary OS, I use Fedora as a primary distro from 8 years, Fedora 33.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SSH keys for authentication</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/posts/use-ssh-keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 04:01:59 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/posts/use-ssh-keys/</guid>
      <description>Set up your first SSH keys Use SSH keys for authentication without password when you are connecting to your server. simple and secure login process.
To Generate a new SSH Key [root@server ~]$ ssh-keygen Generating public/private rsa key pair. Enter file in which to save the key (/root/.ssh/id_rsa): Enter passphrase (empty for no passphrase): Enter same passphrase again: Your identification has been saved in /root/.ssh/id_rsa. Your public key has been saved in /root/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey-o! Tayeh here. 👋</title>
      <link>https://tayeh.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tayeh.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Summary Seasoned DevOps Engineer with diverse extensive background in cloud platforms. Highly motivated, with outstanding work ethics and passion to learn and grow in a world-class dynamic environment.
Technology Stack  Terraform, Packer, Vagrant and Ansible Amazon Web Services (AWS) Google Cloud Platform (GCP) Major Databases Prometheus, Grafana, Loki and ELK stack Jenkins, Jenkins Pipeline (CI/CD) Docker, Podman Container  Experience brief and not current  United Nations International Computing Centre (UNICC), 03/2021 to 11/2021 as a AWS Cloud Administrator Kenan For Information and Technology (Dreams Partner), 08/2019 to Present as a DevOps Engineer Orange Palestine (ISP), 02/2017 to 8/2019 as a Linux Systems Engineer  Certifications  Linux Foundation Certified System Administrator (LFCS) AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF) AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA) and prepare for Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)  Around the web Please feel free to send me an email or a message.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
